I'm traveling through a tunnel right now on a train that's going 200 kilometers an hour.
And above me, there's two and a half kilometers of pure rock.
That's a mile and a half of nothing but mountain.
This tunnel is 57 kilometers long.
It's 35 miles.
It's the longest on the planet.
A few months ago,
I asked the people
who run Switzerland's trains
if they would let me spend a week doing nothing
And in this moment,
I'm in the middle of a race to see
if I can step foot on all 26 Swiss regions,
or cantons, in under 24 hours, but only using public transportation.
And along the way,
locals who responded to my call for stories on our community -driven journalism platform
are going to help me on this challenge.
We have a new plan.
I'm an American who doesn't really understand trains, I'm embarrassed to say.
My country is a country that loves cars.
So I'm here to try to understand what they've built,
how it works,
how it's designed,
what are the crazy engineering feats
that they've done to make this system work,
and most importantly, what can we, outside of this country, learn from it all.
Before my big speed run through the country,
my first item of business is to see
if Swiss engineering is as extreme and rugged as I've heard.
Luckily, I booked a hotel up the hill.
I'm gonna go walk to it
and and see
if they'll let me in, even though it's almost two in the morning.
And with that, good night.